Chris Champness

Repository: github.com/CChampness

Portfolio: cchampness.github.io/CNC-Portfolio Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/chris-champness-4a71775

SUMMARY

Resourceful Web Developer/Software Engineer with 25 years of experience in both very large and very small organizations. Recently attained Georgia Tech's Bootcamp Certificate as a Full Stack Coder. He has been cited as an outstanding team collaborator, as well as a persistent individual contributor. His enthusiasm for the mission is demonstrated by the many successful outcomes on the products and projects he has worked on.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Full-Stack Web Development
JavaScript, CSS, HTML, jQuery, Bootstrap, NodeJS, Express
MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, GraphQL
MVC Handlebars, Github, Insomnia, Heroku
Test Driven Development, Progressive Web Apps, Object Relational Mapping
CRUD, REST, MERN, JWT, React
C++, Embedded Real-time Software

PROJECTS

Talk2Me — Social Media Site for Language Learners

This is a language practice site to help linguaphiles to find one another, make opportunities for conversation practice, and to share resources.

Repository: https://github.com/CChampness/Talk2Me
Deployment: https://moremessages.herokuapp.com/

Materials Trader — Social Media Site for Recycling

Materials Trader is an emerging peer-to-peer bulk recycling network, facilitating the exchange of waste materials among sustainably conscious consumers and businesses.

Repository: https://github.com/djdyer/materials-trader
Deployment: https://materials-trader.herokuapp.com

EditAnywhere — Take-anywhere Text Editor

This text editor runs in the browser and applies syntax highlighting for JavaScript code. It is implemented as a Progressive Web App (PWA).

Repository: https://github.com/CChampness/EditAnywhere

Deployment: https://editanywhere.herokuapp.com

EXPERIENCE

Home Depot, Toccoa GA — Sales Associate

February 2020 - August 2021

Served customers throughout the store by locating materials for them.

Toccoa Hardware, Toccoa GA — *Small Engine Parts Manager* October 2018 - January 2020 Assisted customers by quickly procuring hard-to-find parts for power equipment.

Technical Equipment Distributors, Inc., Melbourne FL — Warehouse Manager

September 2015 - November 2017

Performed shipping and receiving and warehouse management for the wholesale parts business.

Home Depot. Melbourne FL — Sales Associate

April 2014 - September 2015

Guided customers throughout the store and helped them locate needed equipment and materials.

Chris Champness Craftsman, Lafayette, CO — Wood Craftsman

Fabricated custom fine hardwood furniture for customers and wholesalers.

November 2008 - June 2012

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

NCH Software, Denver CO — Software Engineer

Implemented and maintained software utility applications in C++ on Windows for retail and business customers.

InterDigital Communications LLC, King of Prussia PA — Staff Software Engineer

Built, tested, and maintained embedded software in C++ for the 3G High Speed data plane for UMTS.

Essex/CSI (Northrup Grumman), Melbourne FL — Principal Software Engineer

Created, architected, designed, tested, and maintained custom software in C++ for Government customers.

General Electric Transportation (Wabtec), Melbourne FL — *Lead Professional Band Software Engineer*

Designed, tested, and maintained Computer Aided Dispatch system for BNSF, UP, CSX, and NS railroads. Led a team to design and develop an engine monitoring system for mining equipment.

Computer Science Innovations, Melbourne FL — Principal Software Engineer

Architected, designed, built, tested, and maintained custom software in C++ for Government customers.

Harris Corporation, Melbourne FL — Lead Software Engineer

Built, tested, and maintained custom software in C++ for Government customers.

Georgia Tech Research Institute, Atlanta GA — Engineering Research Associate

Wrote and tested software in Pascal for a Government customer.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology — *Certificate in Full-Stack Coding for Web Development*August 2021 - February 2022

Georgia Institute of Technology — B.S. Computer Science